32 chapter 33 of Black Beauty this LibriVox recording is in the public
domain Black Beauty by Anna Su chapter 33 A London Cab Horse jeriah Barker was my new master's
name, but as everyone called him Jerry, I shall do the same. Polly, his wife, was
just as good a match as a man could have.
She was a plump, trim, tidy little woman, with smooth, dark hair, dark eyes, and a
merry little mouth. The boy was 12 years old, a tall, frank, good-tempered lad; and
little Dorothy (Dolly they called her) was her mother all over again, at 8 years old.
They were all wonderfully fond of each other; I never knew such a happy, merry
family before or since.
Jerry had a cab of his own, and two horses, which he drove and attended to
himself. His other horse was a tall, white, rather large boned animal called “Captain”.
He was old now, but when he was young he must have been splendid; he still had a
proud way of holding his head and arching his neck; in fact, he was a
high-bred fine mannered noble old horse, every inch of him. He told me that in his
early youth he went to the Crimean War; he belonged to an officer in the cavalry,
and used to lead the regiment. I will tell more of that
hereafter. The next morning, when I was well groomed Polly and Dolly came into
the yard to see me and make friends.
Harry had been helping his father since the early morning, and had stated his
opinion that I should turn out to be a “regular brick”. Polly brought me a slice of apple,
and Dolly a piece of bread, and made just
as much of me as if I had been the “Black
Beauty” of olden time. It was a great treat to be petted again and talked to
in a gentle voice, and I let them see as
well as I could that I wished to be friendly. Polly thought I was very
handsome, and a great deal too good for a cab, if it were not for the broken
knees. “Of course there's no one to tell us whose fault that was,” said cherry and
as long as I don't know I shall give him the benefit of the doubt; for a firmer,
neater stepper I never rode. We'll call him 'Jack', after the old one— —shall we,
Polly?” “Do,” she said, “for I like to keep a good name
going.” Captain went out in a cab all morning. Harry came in after school to
feed me and give me water. In the afternoon I was put into the cab. Jerry
took as much pains to see if the collar and Bridal fitted comfortably as if he
had been John Manley over again. When the crapper was let out a
hole or two it all fitted well. There was no check rain no curb, nothing but a
plain ring snaffle. What a blessing that was! After driving through the side
street we came to the large cabstand where Jerry had said good night On one
side of this wide street were high houses with wonderful shop fronts, and on
the other was an old church and churchyard, surrounded by iron
palisades. Alongside these iron rails a number of cabs were drawn up, waiting for
passengers; bits of hay were lying about on the ground; some of the men were
standing together talking; some were sitting on their boxes reading the
newspaper; and one or two were feeding their horses with bits of hay, and giving
them a drink of water. We pulled up in the rank at the
back of the last cab. Two or three men came around and began to look at me and
pass their remarks. “Very good for a funeral,” said one.
“Too smart looking said another, shaking his head in a very wise way; “you'll find
find out something wrong one of these fine mornings, or my name isn't
Jones.” “Well,” said Cherry pleasantly, “I suppose I need not find it out until it
finds me out, eh? And if so, I'll keep up my spirits a little
longer.” Then there came up a broad-faced man, dressed in a great gray coat with
great gray cape and great white buttons, a gray hat, and a blue comforter loosely
tied around his neck; his hair was gray, too; but he was a jolly looking fellow,
and the other men made way for him. He looked me all over, as if he had been
going to buy me; and then straightening himself up with a grunt, he said, “He's the
right sort for you, Jerry; I don't care what you gave for him it'll be worth
it.” Thus my character was established on the stand. This man's name was Grant, but he
was called “Gray Grant”, or “Governor Grant”.
He had been the longest on that stand of any of the men, and he took it upon
himself to settle matters and stop disputes. He was generally a good humored
sensible man; but if his temper was a little out, as it was sometimes when he
had drunk too much, nobody liked to come too near his fist, for he could deal a
very heavy blow. The first week of my life as a cab
hor was very trying. I had never been used to London, and the noise, the hurry,
the crowds of horses, carts, and carriages that I had to make my way through made
me feel anxious and harassed; but I soon found that I could perfectly trust my
driver, and then I made myself easy and got used to it. Jerry was as good a
driver as I have ever known, and what was better, he took as much thought for his
horses as he did for himself. He soon found out that I was
willing to work and do my best, and he never laid the whip on me unless it was
gently drawing the end of it over my back when I was to go on; but generally I
knew this quite well by the way in which he took up the rains and I believe his
whip was more frequently stuck up by his side than in his
hand. In a short time I and my master understood each other as well as hen man
can do. In the stable, too, he did all that he could for our comfort. The stalls were
the oldfashioned style, too much on the slope; but he had two movable bars fixed
across the back of our stalls, so that at night, and when we were resting, he just
took off our halters and put up the bars, and thus we could turn about and stand
whichever way we pleased, which is a great comfort. Jerry kept us very clean, and
gave us as much change of food as he could, and always plenty of it; and not
only that, but he always gave us plenty of fresh clean water, which he allowed to
stand by us both night and day, except of course when we came in
warm. Some people say that a horse ought not to drink all he likes; but I know if
we are allowed to drink when we want we drink only a little at a time, and it
does us a good deal more good than swallowing down half a bucket full at a
time, because we have been left without till we are thirsty and
miserable. Some grooms will go home to their beer and leave us for hours with
our dry hay and oats and nothing to moisten them; then of course we gulp down
too much at once, which helps to spoil our breathing and sometimes chills our
stomachs. But the best thing we had here was our Sundays for rest; we worked so
hard in the week that I do not think we
could have kept up to it but for that day; besides, we had then time to enjoy
each other's company. It was on these days that I learned my companions history end of chapter